Kennedy, William; Papers mss132
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Ironweed (Film Version), 1981-1997; Undated; 8; 2.01 cu. ft.
  - Copy of Second Drafts with Author Edits, October 27 1986 (Box 3 (8-Ironweed), Folder 6)
  - Complete Second Draft with No Edits, October 27 1986 (Box 3 (8-Ironweed), Folder 7)
  - Locations, Props, 1986-1987 (Box 3 (8-Ironweed), Folder 8)
  - Info. Regarding Casting, 1986-1987; Undated (Box 3 (8-Ironweed), Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 3 (8-Ironweed), Folder 10)
  - Publicity, 1986-1988; 1993; 1997; Undated (Box 3 (8-Ironweed), Folder 11)
  - Revised and Edited Pages, January 20 1987 (Box 4 (8-Ironweed), Folder 1)
  - Revised Second Draft Script, January 21 1987 (Box 4 (8-Ironweed), Folder 2)
  - Third Draft, January 1987 (Box 4 (8-Ironweed), Folder 3)
  - Ironweed Script Location/Stage Breakdown, January 1987; Undated (Box 4 (8-Ironweed), Folder 4)
  - Photocopy of Helen's Speech by Meryl Streep and Continuity Notes, January 1987; Undated (Box 4 (8-Ironweed), Folder 5)
  - Call Sheets, February-May 1987 (Oversized 5, Folder 6)
  - Revised Pages, March 2 1987 (Box 4 (8-Ironweed), Folder 6)
  - Additions to "Danny" Scene, March 5 1987 (Box 4 (8-Ironweed), Folder 7)
  - Helen Monologue, March 17 1987 (Box 4 (8-Ironweed), Folder 8)
  - Scene Edits, March 17 1987 (Box 4 (8-Ironweed), Folder 9)
  - Copy of Script with Revised Pages, March 17 1987 (Box 5 (8-Ironweed), Folder 1)
  - Taft Entertainment Bound Script (2 copies), March 17 1987 (Box 5 (8-Ironweed), Folder 2-3)
  - Hooverville Extra Lines, May 1987 (Box 5 (8-Ironweed), Folder 4)
  - Filming Schedules, 1987 (Box 5 (8-Ironweed), Folder 5)
  - Radio News Broadcast on War of the Worlds, 1987 (Box 5 (8-Ironweed), Folder 6)
  - "Poor Little Lamb" Lyrics and Information, 1987; Undated (Box 5 (8-Ironweed), Folder 7)
  - Writers Institute Events, 1987; 1997 (Box 5 (8-Ironweed), Folder 8)
  - Finale Notes, Undated (Box 5 (8-Ironweed), Folder 9)
  - Cast of Characters/Continuity Lists, Undated (Box 5 (8-Ironweed), Folder 10)
  - Two Copies of Ironweed Paperback Novel, Used for Scriptwriting with Notes, Undated (Box 5 (8-Ironweed), Folder 11)
  - American Film Article Drafts and Information, 1987-1988 (Box 5 (8-Ironweed), Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Copies and Pull-outs from The Making of Ironweed, 1987-1988; 1993; Undated (Box 6 (8-Ironweed), Folder 1)
  - England/Ireland Reviews, 1988; 1990; Undated (Box 6 (8-Ironweed), Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 6 (8-Ironweed), Folder 3)
  - Trolley Information, Undated (Box 6 (8-Ironweed), Folder 4)
  - "He's Me Pal" Lyrics, Undated (Box 6 (8-Ironweed), Folder 5)
  - Ironweed Logo, Undated (Box 6 (8-Ironweed), Folder 6)
- Quinn's Book, 1981-1988; Undated; 9; 2.91 cu. ft.
  Contains drafts, edited copies, the final version, and galleys of Quinn's Book, published by William Kennedy in 1988. Part of the "Albany Cycle," this novel also involves the extended Phelan family, but focuses on the nineteenth century life and adventures of an ancestor named Daniel Quinn. There are many edited and unedited versions of the manuscript; however, the majority of copies are undated. The archivist tried to arrange these undated drafts in chronological order based upon the edits in each version.
  - Early Versions of Quinn's Book, Undated (Box 1 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 1)
  - Statement of Plan, Summary, Prologue, Undated (Box 1 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 2)
  - Early Pages, Book I, Undated (Box 1 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 3)
  - Original Pages, Began Anew, 1981-1982 (Box 1 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 4)
  - First Draft of Chapters 1 and 2, 1983 (Box 1 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 5)
  - Eight Drafts of Chapter 1, Including Orig. Version, Undated (Box 1 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 6)
  - Five Drafts of Chapters 2, 1983; Undated (Box 1 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 7)
  - One Draft of Chapter 1-3, Undated (Box 1 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 8)
  - Three Drafts of Chapter 3, with Author Notes, 1984; Undated (Box 1 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 9)
  - Refined Copy of First Draft, Pages 1-68, March 1985 (Box 1 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 10)
  - Five Drafts of Chapter 4, with Author Notes, March-May 1985; Undated (Box 1 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 11)
  - Chapters 1-5, Undated (Box 1 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 12)
  - Chapter 5, Undated (Box 1 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 13)
  - Chapters 1-4 with Changes to May 1985 Draft, Undated (Box 1 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 14)
  - Working Drafts and Notes for Chapter 6, May 1985; Undated (Box 2 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 1)
  - Five Drafts of Chapter 6 with Author Notes, including One Prior to January 20, 1986 Draft, Undated (Box 2 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 2)
  - Four Drafts of Chapter 7, Undated (Box 2 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 3)
  - Five Drafts of Chapter 8, including One Prior to and One Following January 20, 1986 Draft, Undated (Box 2 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 4)
  - Chapters 5 Through 8, January 20 1986 (Box 2 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 5)
  - Five Drafts of Chapter 9 with Notes, April 1986; Undated (Box 2 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 6)
  - Two Drafts of Book II, Chapter 1, June 1986; Undated (Box 2 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 7)
  - Book II, Chapter 2 with Author Edits, July 1986 (Box 2 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 8)
  - One Draft of "The Dumb Cake" with Author Edits, Undated (Box 2 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 9)
  - One Draft of "At the Races, At the Ball", September 1986 (Box 2 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 10)
  - Pages with Author Notes, Undated (Box 2 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 11)
  - Pages 1-169 with Edits, Undated (Box 2 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 12)
  - Pages 170-217 with Edits, Undated (Box 3 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 1)
  - Pages 22-221, November 2 1986 (Box 3 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 2)
  - Book II Revised and Edited Pages, Undated (Box 3 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 3)
  - Edited Pages, March 1987 (Box 3 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 4)
  - Book II, Pages 220-282, Undated (Box 3 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 5)
  - Book II, Pages 220-280, Undated (Box 3 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 6)
  - Edited Pages, Pages 220-272, Undated (Box 3 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 7)
  - Reworking of Pages 273-285, Prior to June 11, 1987, Undated (Box 3 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 8)
  - Edited Pages 273-307, Undated (Box 3 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 9)
  - Edited Pages 288-337, 1987 (Box 3 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 10)
  - Edited Pages 293-317, Undated (Box 3 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 11)
  - Edited Pages 306-339, 1987 (Box 4 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 1)
  - Edited Pages 317-334, Undated (Box 4 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 2)
  - Photocopy of Book I, Undated (Box 4 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 3)
  - Photocopy of Book II, Undated (Box 4 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 4)
  - Master Copy with Author's Editing, ca. June 10 1987 (Box 4 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 5-6)
  - Edited Copy, Incomplete (Folder 1 of 2), Undated (Box 4 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 7)
  - Edited Copy, Incomplete (Folder 2 of 2), Undated (Box 5 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 1)
  - Edited Copy of Book I, Undated (Box 5 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 2)
  - Book I, Pages 1-219 with Edits, Undated (Box 5 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 3)
  - Book II, Pages 220-335 with Edits, Undated (Box 5 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 4)
  - Copy of Book I, Undated (Box 5 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 5)
  - Copy of Book II, Undated (Box 5 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 6)
  - Photocopy Book I, Undated (Box 6 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 1)
  - Photocopy Book II, Undated (Box 6 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 2)
  - Book I with Edits, Undated (Box 6 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 3)
  - Book II with Edits, 1987 (Box 6 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 4)
  - Unedited Copy of Book I, Undated (Box 6 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 5)
  - Unedited Copy of Book II, Undated (Box 7 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 1)
  - Unedited Photocopy of Book II, Undated (Box 7 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 2)
  - Copy of Book I with Minor Edits, Undated (Box 7 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 3)
  - Copy of Book II with Minor Edits, Undated (Box 7 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 4)
  - Book I with Gerry Howard Edits, August 1987 (Box 7 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 5)
  - Book II with Gerry Howard Edits, August 1987 (Box 7 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 6)
  - Copy of Final Draft, Book I, 1987 (Box 8 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 1-2)
  - Copy of Final Draft, Book II, 1987 (Box 8 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 3-4)
  - Book I with Proof Reader's Marks, Undated (Box 8 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 5)
  - Book II with Proof Reader's Marks, Undated (Box 9 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 1)
  - Galley Proofs, 1987 (Oversized 4, Folder 4)
  - Copy of Quinn's Book, 1988 (Box 9 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 2)
  - "Dead Matter" and Book Cover, 1988 (Box 9 (9-Quinn's Book), Folder 3)
- Very Old Bones, 1983; 1988-1993; Undated; 10; 4.09 cu. ft.
  William Kennedy continued his writings about the Phelan family with Very Old Bones, his next installment in the "Albany Cycle" of novels published in 1992. This book is set in the 1950s in the city and narrated by Orson Purcell, the out-of-wedlock son of Peter Phelan. The majority of the series consists of manuscript drafts and edited copy, although there are a small number of files containing correspondence, publicity materials, articles and reviews, and excerpts of the novel published in magazines.
  - One Draft of Prologue, 1983 (Box 1 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 1)
  - Early Draft, Undated (Box 1 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 2)
  - Early Draft, October 1988 (Box 1 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 3)
  - Five Drafts with Author Notes, November-December 1988 (Box 1 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 4)
  - Two Drafts and Edited Pages, December 1988 (Box 1 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 5)
  - Superseded Pages, January 1989 (Box 1 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 6)
  - Clean Copy of Winter 1989 Draft, No Editing, ca. January-March 1989 (Box 1 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 7)
  - Chapter 1 Rewrites, June 1989 (Box 1 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 8)
  - Four Working Drafts with Author Notes, June-July 1989 (Box 1 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 9)
  - Cut and Edited Pages, September 1989 (Box 1 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 10)
  - Four Drafts of Book I, Chapter 2 with Author Notes, October 1989 (Box 1 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 11)
  - Two Drafts of Superseded Rewrites, October 1989 (Box 1 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 12)
  - Two Drafts of Rewrites, October 1989 (Box 2 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 1)
  - Three Complete Drafts, November 1989; Undated (Box 2 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 2)
  - Incomplete Draft, Pages 1-87, November 1989 (Box 2 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 3)
  - Rewritten Pages, November 1989; Undated (Box 2 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 4)
  - One Draft "New Master" Copy, Undated (Box 2 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 5)
  - Chapter 4 Rewritten Pages with Author Edits, December 1989-January 1990 (Box 2 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 6)
  - Rewritten Pages, April-May 1990 (Box 2 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 7)
  - Edited and Rewritten Pages, June 1990 (Box 3 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 1)
  - Complete Draft with Author Edits, July 1990 (Box 3 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 2)
  - Two Drafts of Book II's Chapter Three, Undated (Box 3 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 3)
  - Complete Draft of Books I and II with Edits, Superseded September 1990, Undated (Box 3 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 4)
  - Book III, Chapter 1 Rewrites, Superseded October 1990, Undated (Box 3 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 5)
  - Edited Pages, Superseded April, November 1990, Undated (Box 3 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 6)
  - One Draft of Books I and II with Revisions, Superseded December 1990, Undated (Box 3 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 7)
  - Book III Edited and Rewritten Pages, Superseded December 1990, Undated (Box 3 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 8)
  - One Unedited Draft, Pages 1-186, Missing Pages 142-150, Undated (Box 4 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 1)
  - Rewritten and Edited Pages, Superseded January 1991, Undated (Box 4 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 2)
  - Phelan Family Geology and Rewrites, Superseded February 1991, Undated (Box 4 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 3)
  - Edited and Superseded Pages, Superseded March 1991, Undated (Box 4 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 4-5)
  - First Draft, Pages 1-195, 1991 (Box 4 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 6)
  - First Draft, Pages 196-280, 1991 (Box 4 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 7)
  - Second Draft, Pages 1-197, 1991 (Box 5 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 1)
  - Second Draft, Pages 198-280, 1991 (Box 5 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 2)
  - Third Draft with Author Edits, Pages 1-197, 1991 (Box 5 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 3)
  - Third Draft with Author Edits, Pages 198-280, 1991 (Box 5 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 4)
  - Rewritten and Edited Pages, Superseded April-May 1991, Undated (Box 5 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 5)
  - Rewritten and Edited Pages, Superseded June-July 1991, Undated (Box 5 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 6)
  - Written and Edited Pages, Superseded July 1991, Undated (Box 6 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 1-3)
  - Fourth Draft with Author Edits, Pages 1-174, Superseded July 1991, Undated (Box 6 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 4)
  - Fourth Draft with Author Edits, Pages 175-305, Superseded July 1991, Undated (Box 6 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 5)
  - Draft, Unedited, Pages 1-174, July 1991 (Box 7 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 1)
  - Draft, Unedited, Pages 175-305, July 1991 (Box 7 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 2)
  - Rewritten and Edited Pages, Superseded August 1991, Undated (Box 7 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 3)
  - Rewritten and Edited Pages, Superseded September 1991, Undated (Box 7 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 4-5)
  - Rewritten and Edited Pages, Undated (Box 8 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 1)
  - Second to Last Draft, Pages 1-189, September 1991 (Box 8 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 2)
  - Second to Last Draft, Pages 190-361, September 1991 (Box 8 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 3)
  - Penultimate Draft, Copy, Pages 1-189, September 1991 (Box 8 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 4)
  - Penultimate Draft, Copy, Pages 190-361, September 1991 (Box 8 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 5)
  - Rewritten and Edited Pages, 1991 (Box 9 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 1)
  - Penultimate Draft, Pages 1-204, Sent October 1991, ca. September 1991 (Box 9 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 2)
  - Penultimate Draft, Pages 205-361, Sent October 1991, ca. September 1991 (Box 9 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 3)
  - "Final" Draft, Viking Copy, Pages 1-189, October 1991 (Box 9 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 4)
  - "Final" Draft, Viking Copy, Pages 190-363, October 1991 (Box 9 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 5)
  - Final Draft, A. Silverman Copy with Notes, Pages 1-189, October 1991 (Box 9 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 6)
  - Final Draft, A. Silverman Copy with Notes, Pages 1-189, October 1991 (Box 10 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 1)
  - Rewritten Pages, Superseded October-November 1991, Undated (Box 10 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 2)
  - Photocopy of Penguin USA Manuscript, Pages 1-189, November 1991 (Box 10 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 3)
  - Photocopy of Penguin USA Manuscript, Pages 190-363, November 1991 (Box 10 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 4)
  - Printer's Copy of Very Old Bones, Pages 1-189, October 1991 (Box 10 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 5)
  - Printer's Copy of Very Old Bones, Pages 190-363, October 1991 (Box 10 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 6)
  - Author's Set of Galley Proofs, December 1991 (Box 11 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 1)
  - Author's Set of Galley Proofs, with Handwritten Edits, December 1991 (Box 11 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 2)
  - Master Galleys, December 1991 (Box 11 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 3-4)
  - Publicity Materials, 1990-1993; Undated (Box 11 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 5-6)
  - Rewritten Paragraphs for "Exile", December 1991 (Box 11 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 7)
  - Viking Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 12 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 1)
  - Publication Information, 1991-1992 (Box 12 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 2)
  - Playboy Excerpts, 1991-1992; Undated (Box 12 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 3)
  - The Recorder, Volume 6, Number 1, Summer 1992 (Box 12 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 4)
  - Articles, Reviews, Clippings, 1992; Undated (Box 12 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 5)
  - "Fan" Mail, 1992; Undated (Box 12 (10-Very Old Bones), Folder 6)
  - Playboy Corrected Galleys, 1992 (Oversized 6, Folder 1)
  - Book Reviews and Profiles, 1992 (Oversized 6, Folder 2)
- Riding the Yellow Trolley Car, 1946-1999; Undated; 11; 1.86 cu. ft.
  This series includes draft copy, galleys, research materials, correspondence, and notes used to prepare William Kennedy's Riding the Yellow Trolley Car, a collection of his essays, articles, and reviews written across four decades. This second nonfiction book from Kennedy appeared in 1993. Of note is the earliest item within the collection, a short story entitled "Eggs" from 1946 which Kennedy submitted to Collier's: The National Weekly for consideration. In addition there are files about publicity, including a book tour, reviews, and fan mail. Please note the overall dates for the series are not inclusive.
  - Short Story "Eggs", 1946 (Box 1 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 1)
  - Guys and Dolls Script and Articles, 1950-1992 (Box 1 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 2)
  - John Steinbeck Information, 1962; 1968; 1989; Undated (Box 1 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 3)
  - Unused Articles with Notes, 1967-1992; Undated (Box 1 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 4)
  - One Draft "Roberta Sue Ficker", 1968 (Box 1 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 5)
  - Articles and Author Notes Regarding Paul McCartney, 1969; Undated (Box 1 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 6)
  - Photocopies of "Trolley Car" Articles, 1964-1987 (Box 1 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 7)
  - One Draft of "Robert Penn Warren", 1973 (Box 1 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 8)
  - Correspondence and Articles, 1974; 1985; 1992-1993; Undated (Box 1 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 9)
  - Original William Kennedy Articles, 1974-1988; Undated (Box 1 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 10)
  - Kennedy Articles Used for Book I, 1982; 1985; Undated (Box 1 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 11)
  - Louis "Satchmo" Armstrong, Author Notes and Clippings, 1983; 1992; 1999; Undated (Box 1 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 12)
  - Notes and Photocopies, 1984; 1987; 1989-1990; 1992 (Box 1 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 13)
  - "Soto," Articles and Information, 1988; 1992; Undated (Box 1 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 14)
  - Drafts and Correspondence Regarding Article "Do the Homeless Have Souls?", 1988-1991 (Box 1 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 15)
  - Writings and Articles Regarding "Dana's Hiccups", 1989; 1992; Undated (Box 2 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 1)
  - One Draft of "Norman Mailer Speech", 1991 (Box 2 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 2)
  - "Two Grandfathers" Correspondence and Drafts, 1991-1992; Undated (Box 2 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 3)
  - Eight Drafts of "All My Days Are the Same", 1991-1992 (Box 2 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with Viking Press, 1991-1993 (Box 2 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 5)
  - Notes and Drafts of the Table of Contents, 1992; Undated (Box 2 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 6)
  - Twelve Drafts of the "Introduction", 1992 (Box 2 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 7)
  - Copyright Correspondence, 1992 (Box 2 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 8)
  - Nine Drafts of "Guys and Dolls," Writings, 1992 (Box 2 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 9)
  - Guys and Dolls Script Articles and Information, 1992 (Box 2 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 10)
  - Guys and Dolls Book Cover, 1992 (Box 2 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 11)
  - Ten Drafts of "How I Became a Baseball Fan" with Author Notes, 1992; Undated (Box 2 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 12)
  - Four Drafts of "Has Anybody Here Seen Runyon?", 1992 (Box 2 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 13)
  - First Set of Galley Proofs, 1992 (Oversized 7, Folder 1)
  - Galleys, ca. 1992 (Oversized 7, Folder 2-3)
  - Author's Set of Galleys, 1992 (Oversized 7, Folder 4-6)
  - Damon Runyon Information, 1992; 1994; Undated (Box 2 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 14)
  - 1993 Book Tour Publicity, 1992-1993; Undated (Box 2 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 15)
  - Publicity, Correspondence, Clippings and Articles, 1992-1994 (Box 2 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 16)
  - Galleys, Publicity, and Research Material, 1992-1993; Undated (Oversized 6, Folder 3)
  - Photocopies of Book Materials, 1993 (Box 3 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 1)
  - Fan Mail, 1993 (Box 3 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 2)
  - Reviews, 1993 (Box 3 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 3)
  - Viking Book Guide, 1993 (Box 3 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 4)
  - "Robert Frost" Draft for National Observer, Undated (Box 3 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 5)
  - Photocopy of "Part One", Undated (Box 3 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 6)
  - Photocopy of "Part Two," Examining Writers, Undated (Box 3 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 7)
  - Photocopy of "Parts Three and Four", Undated (Box 3 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 8)
  - Photocopy of "Parts Five and Six", Undated (Box 3 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 9)
  - Photocopy of Pages 1-199, Undated (Box 3 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 10)
  - Photocopy of Pages 200-402, Undated (Box 3 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 11)
  - Photocopy of Pages 403-494, Undated (Box 4 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 1)
  - Riding the Yellow Trolley Car Bookcovers, Undated (Box 4 (11-Riding the Yellow Trolley Car), Folder 2)
- The Flaming Corsage, 1993-1997; 2001; Undated; 12; 2.93 cu. ft.
  For his next volume in his "Albany Cycle," William Kennedy returned to recurrent characters Edward and Katrina Daugherty, first introduced in Billy Phelan's Greatest Game. Kennedy charts their lives and subsequent, turbulent marriage in the city between 1884 and 1912 in The Flaming Corsage, published in 1996. The series includes multiple drafts and edited manuscripts, book tour materials, cover artwork, reviews, articles, correspondence, and information about the audio version of the book.
  - Prologue and Chapter One Drafts, 1993-1994 (Box 1 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 1)
  - Chapter One Drafts, 1993-1994 (Box 1 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 2)
  - Chapter Two Drafts, 1993 (Box 1 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 3)
  - Early Draft of Chapter 1 and 2, Summary, 1993 (Box 1 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 4)
  - Early Draft "Untitled Novel", 1994 February (Box 1 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 5)
  - Chapter 2 Drafts, 1994 (Box 1 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 6)
  - Rewritten and Edited Pages, 1994 (Box 1 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 7)
  - Chapter 3 Drafts, 1994 (Box 1 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 8)
  - Rewrites and Edits, 1994 (Box 1 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 9)
  - First Draft with Edited Pages, 1994 (Box 2 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 1)
  - "Edward" Drafts, 1994 (Box 2 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 2)
  - Second Drafts, 1994 (Box 2 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 3)
  - Rewritten Pages, 1994 (Box 2 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 4-5)
  - Rewrites and Edits, 1994 (Box 2 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 6)
  - Third Draft, 1994 (Box 2 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 7)
  - Rewrites and Edits, 1995 (Box 3 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 1)
  - Partial "New" Third Draft, 1995 (Box 3 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 2)
  - Rewritten and Edited Pages, 1995 (Box 3 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 3-4)
  - Partial Chronological Draft, 1995 (Box 3 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 5)
  - Incomplete Draft, 1995 (Box 3 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 6)
  - Photocopy of Complete Draft, 1995 May (Box 3 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 7)